Guide to the Helen and Newton Harrison Papers M1797
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Project Files, 1969-2011
  - Subseries 58. Santa Fe, 1994-1995, 2002-2008
    - Santa Fe; Research, Water, 1994-1998 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Santa Fe; Research, Water, 2002-2004 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Santa Fe; Research, Water, undated (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Santa Fe; Santa Fe Art Institute literature, 2003 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Santa Fe; Santa Fe Watershed: Lessons from the Genius of Place exhibition, Santa Fe Art Institute, 2004-2005 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Santa Fe; Schedules, 2004, undated (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Santa Fe; Sketches, undated (Flat-box 270, Folder 19)
    - Santa Fe; Text, undated (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Santa Fe; Travel information, 1995, 2003 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 59. Braddock, 2003-2005
    This subseries consists of contact information, contracts and agreements, correspondence, maps, designs, conference material, photographic material, planning, notes, proposals, and research. The Harrisons were invited to Braddock, Pennsylvania, by Carnegie Mellon University’s Institute for Creative Inquiry. Braddock is an economically depressed former steel town on the Monongahela River next to Pittsburgh. The Harrisons designed a rainwater catchment system using the city’s sewers, water percolation, and gardens (urban parks) to alleviate the river’s sewage problem by reducing the overflow. In this design, the collected water would slowly make its way back to the river in a purified form via sponge phenomenon. The work is called “Fecal Matters: A Proposal for Braddock, North Braddock, and the Lands Above.” As part of this project, the Harrisons attended the Monongahela Conferences organized by colleague Tim Collins. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Braddock; Contact information, 2003-2005 (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Braddock; Contact information, undated (Flat-box 270, Folder 20)
    - Braddock; Contracts and agreements, 2005 (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Braddock; Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Braddock; Correspondence, 2005, circa 2003-2005 (Box 108, Folder 11)
    - Braddock; Design, undated (Map-folder 370)
      Sticky back
    - Braddock; Design, undated (Map-folder 371)
    - Braddock; Designs, undated (Map-folder 457)
    - Braddock; Designs for combined sewer overflows in wet weather, undated (Map-folder 372)
    - Braddock; Map, undated (Flat-box 270, Folder 21)
    - Braddock; Map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, 2004-2005 (Map-tube MT #10)
    - Braddock; Maps, 1979, undated (Map-folder 458)
    - Braddock; Maps, 2004, undated (Box 108, Folder 12)
    - Braddock; Maps, undated (Map-folder 373)
    - Braddock; Monongahela Conference, On Post Industrial Community Development, 2003-2004 (Box 108, Folder 13)
    - Braddock; Monongahela Conference, Paper, 2003-2005 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Braddock; Monongahela Conference, Press, 2003 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Braddock; Monongahela Conference, Shifting the Paradigm - The Monongahela Conference III, 2005 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Braddock; Photographic material, Contact sheets, 2005 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Braddock; Photographic material, Negatives, 2005 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Braddock; Photographic material, Photographs, 2005 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Braddock; Planning and notes, 1997, 2003-2005 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Braddock; Proposals, 2005 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Braddock; Research, 2001, 2004-2005 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Braddock; Research, undated (Flat-box 279, Folder 6)
      Fish posters
    - Braddock; Residency artists, undated (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - Braddock; Topographical map of Braddock, Pennsylvania, 2004-2005 (Map-tube MT #11)
    - Braddock; Topographical map of Braddock, Pennsylvania, 2004-2005 (Map-tube MT #12)
    - Braddock; Topographical map of Braddock, Pennsylvania with title "Lost watersheds and drainage patterns", 2004-2005 (Map-tube MT #13)
    - Braddock; Topographical map of Braddock, Pennsylvania, 2004-2005 (Map-tube MT #14)
    - Braddock; Topographical map of Braddock, Pennsylvania, 2004-2005 (Map-tube MT #15)
    - Braddock; Topographical map of Braddock, Pennsylvania with title "Looking for Braddock's Fields: A project of the Ground Zero Action Network", 2004-2005 (Map-tube MT #16)
  - Subseries 60. Flevoland, 2003-2004
    This subseries consists of contact information, contracts and agreements, correspondence, publicity, exhibition information, financial records, maps, meeting information, schedules, photographic material, planning, notes, proposals, research, and writings. For this project, the Harrisons were invited to Flevoland, a province in the Netherlands, to reflect on the cultural landscape and the province’s Provincial Plan. The Harrisons proposed a green connecting zone from Bodensee to the Delta. There is also material about the De Verbeelding, where this project was exhibited under the name Fluid Vistas Flevoland. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Flevoland; Contact information, 2004 (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Flevoland; Contracts and agreements, 2004 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Flevoland; Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 109, Folder 13)
    - Flevoland; De Verbeelding, Fluid Vistas Flevoland art project, General Information, 2003-2005 (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - Flevoland; De Verbeelding, Fluid Vistas Flevoland art project, Harrisons' involvement with Fluid Vistas Flevoland #2 Kasteel Groeneveld - Staatsbosbeheer, 2003-2005 (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - Flevoland; De Verbeelding, General information, 2003-2004, undated (Box 109, Folder 16)
    - Flevoland; Fragments to Mass - A Trans Island Nature Reserve For Southern Flevopolder, 2004 (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - Flevoland; Invoices, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Flevoland; Invoices [RESTRICTED], 2004 (Box 261, Folder 7)
    - Flevoland; Maps, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Flevoland; Maps, 2004 (Flat-box 270, Folder 22)
    - Flevoland; Maps, undated (Map-folder 374)
    - Flevoland; Meetings and schedules, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Flevoland; On Evidence Based Constructs and Prima Facia Constructs, undated (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Flevoland; Photographic material, Aerial from the Record Office in Flevoland (Copies), undated (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Flevoland; Planning and notes, 2003-2004 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Flevoland; Proposals, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 7)
      Includes text
    - Flevoland; Research, 1984, 2000-2003 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Flevoland; Research, 2004, undated (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Flevoland; Research, undated (Map-folder 459)
  - Subseries 61. Schelde River, 2003-2004
    This subseries consists of contact information, contracts and agreements, correspondence, maps, planning, notes, proposals, research, schedules, and text. For this project, the Harrisons proposed to establish a cultural and ecological corridor along the Schelde River from Ghent to Antwep in Belgium. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Schelde River; Contact information, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - Schelde River; Contracts and agreements, 2003-2004 (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - Schelde River; Contracts and agreements [RESTRICTED], 2003-2004 (Box 261, Folder 8)
    - Schelde River; Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 261, Folder 9)
    - Schelde River; Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Schelde River; Invoices [RESTRICTED], 2003-2004 (Box 261, Folder 10)
    - Schelde River; Maps, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Schelde River; Maps, undated (Flat-box 275, Folders 18-19)
    - Schelde River; Maps, undated (Map-folder 460)
    - Schelde River; Planning and notes, 2003-2004 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Schelde River; Proposals, 2003-2004 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Schelde River; Research, 1999-2000, 2002-2004, undated (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Schelde River; Schedules, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Schelde River; Text, 2003-2004 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Schelde River; Workshop participants, Sint-Pietrsabbey, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 62. Chiemsee Art, 2004
    This subseries consists of correspondence, designs, planning, notes, maps, and research. Peter Strauss invited the Harrisons to the lakeside region of Chiemgau in Southern Bavaria to participate in a project for the Center for Landscape Art. For this project, the Harrisons designed a complex, looping path to connect towns to each other. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Chiemsee; chiemSEE ART European Centre for Landscape Art, 2003-2004 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Chiemsee; Correspondence, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Chiemsee; Design, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Chiemsee; Designs, 2004 (Flat-box 270, Folder 23)
    - Chiemsee; Maps of Bad Endorf, 2004 (Flat-box 270, Folder 24)
    - Chiemsee; On Island Ecology in part from the Red List: A Hot Spot for Bad Endorf, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Chiemsee; Peter F. Strauss, 2001-2004 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Chiemsee; Planning and notes, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Chiemsee; Research, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 63. Bay Area Project, 2005-2009
    This subseries consists of contact information, correspondence, project descriptions, meeting minutes, planning, notes, proposals, research, text, and writings. For this project, the Harrisons examined the Sacramento/San Joaquin Drain Basins and the Bays at San Francisco, focusing on the rising of oceans and resettlement. The full name of this project is “The Bay Area: The Lands Above, The Waters Below, The Ocean Beyond.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Bay Area; The Artists and their working group, undated (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Bay Area; Attendees at BCDC (Bay Conservation and Development Commission) / Bay Eco Art Project, 2/15/2006 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Bay Area; The Bay Center, undated (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Bay Area; Consciously Evolving Bay Area's White Paper, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Bay Area; Contact information, undated (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Bay Area; Correspondence, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Bay Area; Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - Bay Area; Correspondence, 2009, undated (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Bay Area; Descriptions, 2006, undated (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Bay Area; Focusing the Bay Area's Vision presentation, 2006 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Bay Area; Meeting minutes of the Bay Area Project, 2005-2006 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Bay Area; Planning and notes, undated (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Bay Area; Proposals, 2005-2006 (Box 112, Folders 6-7)
    - Bay Area; Research, 2005-2006, undated (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Bay Area; Rising Tides competition through the San Francisco Bay and Development Commission, 2009 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Bay Area; Saving the Bay: A Story of San Francisco, 2009 (Box 112, Folder 10)
      Folder contains only a referral to location.
      Item removed to be housed with AV material in Box bav20. Format: DVD
    - Bay Area; Text, undated (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - Bay Area; Where the Rivers Meet the Sea: An Artistic, Ecological Inquiry into the Possible Future of the San Francisco Bay Area, undated (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 64. Memorial Orchard for Pasadena, 2005
    This subseries consists of correspondence, designs, planning, notes, and proposals. The project was sponsored by the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California. The Harrisons designed an orchard that students from Pasadena High School would tend and harvest. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Memorial Orchard for Pasadena; Correspondence, 2005 (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Memorial Orchard for Pasadena; Designs, 2005 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - Memorial Orchard for Pasadena; Planning and notes, 2005 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - Memorial Orchard for Pasadena; Proposals, 2004-2005 (Box 112, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 65. Yorkshire, 2005
    This subseries consists of correspondence, planning, notes, and research for a project that grew out of Greenhouse Britain. The Harrisons studied regional agriculture for this project. Funding fell through, and it was never completed. The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    See also Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 66. Greenhouse Britain; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 69. Devon; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 70. Landmark Wales
    - Yorkshire, 2005, undated (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 66. Greenhouse Britain, 2006-2009
    This subseries consists of vendor and collaborator information, budgets, contact information, correspondence, project descriptions, exhibition information, catalogs, meeting information, photographic material, planning, notes, presentation information, press, proposals, posters, research, and text, as well as material from the Sheffield University charrette. Funded by Department of Food and Rural Affairs (DEFRA) and Gunpowder Park’s Bright Sparks program, the project focused on the rising of waters and the resettlement of people because of climate change. Key partners were the Tyndall Centre for Climate Change Research, the Institute of Grassland and Environmental Research at North Wyke in Devon, the Landscape Department at the University of Sheffield, and MIRIAD Research Centre at Manchester Metropolitan University. This work proposed lectures and seminars in venues across Britain along with a traveling exhibition. The full title of this work is “Greenhouse Britain: Losing Ground, Graining Wisdom.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    See also Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 64. Yorkshire; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 69. Devon; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 70. Landmark Wales
    - Greenhouse Britain; Academy Studios, 2007 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Greenhouse Britain; APG Architects, 2006, circa 2006-2008 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Greenhouse Britain; APG Architects, undated (Flat-box 279, Folder 7)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Bright Sparks Lea (Lee) Valley, 2006-2008 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Budgets, undated (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Contact information, undated (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 2005 (Box 261, Folder 11)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, January 2007 - March 2007 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, April 2007 - May 2007 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, June 2007 - July 2007 (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, August 2007 - September 2007 (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, October 2007 - November 2007 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, December 2007 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, January 2008 - February 2008 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, March 2008 - September 2008 (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Correspondence, 2009, circa 2006-2009 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Greenhouse Britain; DEFRA (Department for Environment Food and Rural Affairs), 2007-2008 (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Descriptions, undated (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Exhibitions, Exhibition components and Addendum, 2007 (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Exhibitions, Centre for the Contemporary Art and the Natural World, Haldon Forest, Exeter, England, 2007 (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Exhibitions, Greater London Authority's City Hall, London England, 2008 (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Exhibitions, Knowle West Media Centre, Knowle West, Bristol, England, 2007 (Box 114, Folder 11)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Exhibitions, Taiwan (Exhibition cancelled), 2007-2008 (Box 114, Folder 12)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Greenhouse Britain: Losing Ground, Gaining Wisdom, 2007 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Greeninfo Network, 2007 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Images, Animals, undated (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Images, Plants and vegetation, undated (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Initial storyboard for "In Defense of Bristol", 2007 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Knowle West, 2008 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Knowle West, undated (Flat-box 275, Folder 20)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Meetings, 2006-2007 (Box 115, Folder 7)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Models, ATOPIA, 2008 (Box 115, Folder 8)
      David Turnbull
    - Greenhouse Britain; Models, Tyndall Centre for Climate Change, 2007 (Box 115, Folder 9)
      Professor Robert J. Nicholls
    - Greenhouse Britain; Photographs, Photo thumbnails, undated (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Photographs, Photos of Pennine Village site (Copies), undated (Box 115, Folders 11-12)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Photographs, Unused photo prints (Copies), undated (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Planning and notes, 2006-2007 (Box 115, Folder 14)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Poster, undated (Flat-box 279, Folder 8)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Presentations, Greenhouse Britain: A Work by the Harrison Studio Britain and Associates, 2007 (Box 115, Folder 15)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Presentations, Old Market Hall Film and Digital Media Centre, Shrewsbury, England, 2008 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Presentations, Unidentified transcript, undated (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Press, 2007-2008 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Proposals, 2006-2007 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Research, 2004-2005, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Sheffield University charrette, Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Sheffield University charrette, Material from charrette, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - Greenhouse Britain; Text, 2007, undated (Box 116, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 67. Terre Haute, 1992-1995, 2006-2007
    This subseries consists of contact information, correspondence, project descriptions, travel information, planning, notes, research, maps, and text, as well as material about the Rose Hulman Institute of Technology (RHIT) and Saint Mary-of-the-Woods. The Harrisons first became involved with Terre Haute, Indiana, in 1992 through an invitation to discuss a project with Indiana State University. The project was not completed, but they met researcher Steve Letsinger. In 2007, Letsinger, working as the art curator at RHIT, invited the Harrisons to participate in a conference and to study the Wabash River. This project is also named “Terre Haute: The First City in the History of Cities” and “Wabash River Project: A Floodplain Transformation for Terre Haute.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Terre Haute; Contact information, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - Terre Haute; Correspondence, 1992-1995, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - Terre Haute; Description, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - Terre Haute; Itinerary and travel information for the Harrisons' visit, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - Terre Haute; Maps, 1975, 1977, 2006 (Map-folder 461)
    - Terre Haute; Planning and notes, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - Terre Haute; Research, Wabash River, 2004 (Box 116, Folder 14)
    - Terre Haute; Research, Wabash River, 2006-2007 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Terre Haute; Research, Wabash River, 2007 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      Packet
    - Terre Haute; Research, Wabash River, undated (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Terre Haute; Research proposal for the Wabash River watershed, undated (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Terre Haute; Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology, Biographical information, 2007 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Terre Haute; Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology, CD's, 2007 (Box 117, Folder 6)
      Two items removed to be housed with computer media / born digital material. Box 264 Item #: M1797_CM343 Title: RHIT – Wabash River Wetlands Info, 2007 Format: CD
      Item #: M1797_CM342 Title: RHIT Wabash/Indiana – Harrisons Format: CD
    - Terre Haute; Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology, Conference, Presentations by the Harrisons: Watersheds Large and Small: The Endangered Meadows of Europe and Transforming Terre Haute, 2007 (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Terre Haute; Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology, Conference, Sustainable Transformations: Technology and Its Environments, 2007 (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - Terre Haute; Saint Mary-of-the-Woods literature, undated (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - Terre Haute; Text, undated (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 68. Traunstein, 2006
    This subseries consists of correspondence, financial records, proposals, research, and a written summary of the Harrisons’ visit by Martin Schneider-Jacoby. The Harrisons were originally invited to Traunstein, north of Munich in Bavaria, to study flood control issues at the Traun Drain Basin (Einzugsgebiet Traun). Using the concept of the “Stability Domain,” the Harrisons expanded their view to include the entire drain basin. The concept examines the European Peninsula from the high ground downward, as an extremely complex, interlocked, mutually influencing system of watersheds. The full title of this project is “The Traunstein Drain Basin: Toward Becoming a Domain of Stability.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Traunstein; Correspondence, 2006 (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - Traunstein; Financial, 2006 (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Traunstein; Financial [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 261, Folder 12)
    - Traunstein; Proposals, 2006 (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - Traunstein; Research, 2005-2006, undated (Box 117, Folder 14)
      Item removed to be housed with computer media / born-digital material. Box 264 Item #: M1797_CM 378 Title: Daten Traun Format: CD
    - Traunstein; Traun Basin Visit, 2005-2006, undated (Box 117, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 69. Devon, 2007-2009
    This subseries consists of correspondence, maps, planning, notes, a proposal, research, writings, and grant information. Based in Dartmoor, an area of moorland in South Devon, this project grew out of Greenhouse Britain. The focus of this project was sustainable land management and real communities. This project is also known as “Dartmoor Stability Domain: Sustainable Landscapes for Devon.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    See also Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 64. Yorkshire; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 66. Greenhouse Britain; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 70. Landmark Wales
    - Devon; "A Story of Becoming: Landscape Creation Through An Art/Science Dynamic", 2009 (Box 117, Folder 16)
      by Les Firbank, Helen Mayer Harrison, Newton Harrison, David Haley, and Bruce Griffith
    - Devon; Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Devon; Correspondence, 2009 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Devon; Dartmoor Sustainable Development Fund grant application, 2009 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Devon; Maps, undated (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Devon; Planning and notes, 2009, undated (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Devon; Proposal, undated (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Devon; Research, 2001, undated (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 70. Landmark Wales, 2007
    This subseries consists of Landmark Wales, Living Landmarks Project competition information for the Landmark Wales, Living Landmarks Project; correspondence; proposals; and research. This British Isles project grew out of Greenhouse Britain, and at its core are concepts of climate change, the rising of waters, and the resettlement of people. The full title of this project is “Wales: Envisioning the Mountains and the Valleys and the Rising of Waters.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    See also Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 64. Yorkshire; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 66. Greenhouse Britain; Series 2. Project Files, Subseries 69. Devon
    - Landmark Wales; Competition information, 2007 (Box 118, Folder 8)